farmersalmanac.com 2018-12-23

# Privacy Policy and Terms of Usage - Farmers’ Almanac

**Privacy Policy and Terms of Usage**  
Farmers’ Almanac and its parent company Geiger, recognize the importance of protecting the privacy of all information provided by users of our websites, subscribers to our Almanac, recipients of our e-mail newsletters, and all of our customers. You are able to visit much of this website and enjoy many of our articles and features without providing any personally identifiable information. Sometimes, however, we do require personally identifiable information to provide you with additional web site features, products and services that you request. The types of personally identifiable information that may be collected on these pages and elsewhere include, but are not limited to: name, address, e-mail address, telephone number, fax number, credit card information (for online store purchases only), and information about your interests in, and use of, various products, programs, and services.

Farmers’ Almanac is committed to protecting the privacy of users of this web site and the information you provide.

**Orders**

If you purchase a product or service from us, we request certain personally identifiable information from you on our order form. You must provide contact information (such as name, phone number, email, and shipping address) and financial information (such as credit card number, expiration date). We use this information for billing purposes and to fill your orders. If we have trouble processing an order, we will use this information to contact you.

**Surveys or Contests**

We may provide you the opportunity to participate in contests or surveys on our site. If you participate, we will request certain personally identifiable information from you. Participation in these surveys or contests is completely voluntary and you therefore have a choice whether or not to disclose this information. The requested information typically includes contact information (such as name and shipping address) and demographic information (such as zip code).

We use this information to notify contest winners and award prizes, to monitor site traffic or personalize the site (in the case of anonymous information collected in surveys), or to send participants an email newsletter.  
We may use a third party service provider to conduct these surveys or contests; that company will be prohibited from using our users’ personally identifiable information for any other purpose. We will not share the personally identifiable information you provide through a contest or survey with other third parties unless we give you prior notice and choice.  
**Special Offers, Updates and Newsletters**

We will occasionally send out information on products, services, special deals, and promotions. You can sign up for these emails from us on every page of the site. Out of respect for your privacy, we present the option not to receive these types of communications.

**Customer Service**

Based upon the personally identifiable information you provide us, we will send you a welcoming email to verify your username and password. We will also communicate with you in response to your inquiries, to provide the services you request, and to manage your account. We will communicate with you by email or telephone, in accordance with your wishes.  
**Other Information**

We share your mailing address with some carefully screened vendors whom we feel may provide products and services that will be of benefit to you. If you do not want us to share your mailing information please contact us here and we will opt you out of these offers.  
**Agents**

We use outside suppliers and shipping companies to fulfill some orders. These companies do not retain, share, store or use personally identifiable information for any other purposes.

**Service Providers**

We use other third parties to provide software and hosting services for our site. We do not share any personally identifiable information with these service providers.  
**Legal Disclaimer**

We reserve the right to disclose your personally identifiable information as required by law and when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or to comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process served on our web site.  
**Choice/Opt-out**

We provide you the opportunity to ‘opt-out’ of having your personally identifiable information used for certain purposes, when we ask for this information. For example, if you purchase a product/service but do not wish to receive any additional marketing material from us, you can indicate your preference.

If you no longer wish to receive our newsletter and promotional communications, you may opt-out of receiving them by following the instructions included in each newsletter.

If you wish to opt out of targeted Video Advertising you may do so here[: http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp  
](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp)  
If you wish to opt out of targeted display and content ads, you may do so here: <http://www.google.com/ads/preferences/plugin/browsers.html>

**Log Files**

As is true of most web sites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information includes Internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, Internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and click stream data.  
We, and our advertisers, use this information, which does not identify individual users, to analyze trends, to administer the site, to track users’ movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole.

**Cookies**

A cookie is a small text file that is stored on a user’s computer for record-keeping purposes. We use cookies on this site. We do not link the information we store in cookies to any personally identifiable information you submit while on our site.  
We do not use session specific cookies on this site. A session cookie expires when you close you browser. A persistent cookie remains on your hard drive for an extended period of time. You can remove persistent cookies by following directions provided in your Internet browser’s “help” file.

We use persistent cookies to store such data as customer id, basket id, and previously viewed items. Advertisers may also use cookies, if enabled, to match advertisements to your browsing history.  
If you reject cookies, you may still use our site, but your ability to use some areas of our site, such as contests or surveys, will be limited.
